Feeling all beat by 6 PM.
[The Tamo-san Hour Smile! Is that Good?]
♪♪｢夕方６時は ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞ｣
Everything's still all good.
♪♪｢やっぱり どうでもよきかな｣
Getting all bitchy by 6 PM.
♪♪｢夕方６時は ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞ
明日も どうでもよきかな｣
Tomorrow will be all good.
♪♪｢このおまけ 誰が望んだ｣
Who actually watches this segment?
No way anyone could possibly want this!
♪♪(多毛)｢そんなの誰も
望んでるわけねえだろ お前！｣
The staff came up with it on a whim!
♪♪｢ｽﾀｯﾌの思いつきに
決まってんだろ！｣
Yosan wo agete.
♪♪(よきかな中年隊)
｢Give me money 予算を上げて｣
Give me money!
♪♪｢今どき４対３なんて ｳﾁぐらい｣
We're the only ones using 4:3 in this day and age.
♪♪｢何年やっても お値段据え置き｣
After all these years, the costs haven't changed!
♪♪｢すっかり板についた土下座癖｣
Completely grown accustomed to getting down on my knees.
♪♪｢すみません
ﾎﾝﾄ来週から気をつけます！｣
Sorry about that. I'll watch myself next week!
Laugh away! Bitchin' sparking! Yay!
♪♪｢笑ってよきかな
ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞｽﾊﾟｰｷﾝ！ ｲｴ～ｲ！｣
Project X.
[Note: Project X is a Japanese TV documentary series.]
♪♪｢ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ Ｘ｣
[Note: Tomoro Taguchi is the Japanese voice actor who narrates in Project X.]
Tomoro Taguchi!
♪♪｢田口ﾄﾓﾛｦ｣
♪♪｢男はつらいよ｣
It's hard to be a man.
[Note: From Japanese Film series "Otoko wa Tsuraiyo".]
Gajiro Sato.
[Note: Gajiro Sato played "Genkichi" in "It's hard being a man" series.]
♪♪｢佐藤ｶﾞｼﾞﾛｦ｣
♪♪(よきかな中年隊)
｢よきかな よきかな｣
It's all good. It's all good.
Sato!
[Note: Word play on Tomoro Taguchi and Gajiro Sato.]
♪♪｢佐藤！｣
♪♪｢ﾄﾓﾛｦ｣
Tomoro!
早速 ｺｰﾅｰです｡
We'll move on to the next segment.
["Shocked by the Phone"]
♪♪～
こんばんは｡
Good evening.
今日は暑かったね｡
It was pretty warm out today.
もうすぐ 梅雨にもなるしね｡
We're going to hit the rainy season soon.
Will you still be watching tomorrow?
明日も見てくれるかな？
We have a ten kilometer course from the riverbed to OEDO TV.
この河川敷から
大江戸ﾃﾚﾋﾞまでおよそ10ｷﾛのｺｰｽ｡
If anybody on the team gives up, that team is immediately disqualified!
ﾁｰﾑの中で １人でも
棄権者 ｷﾞﾌﾞｱｯﾌﾟする者が出れば➡
そのﾁｰﾑは 失格になります！
(新八)たかち～ん！
Takachin!
It's bouncing back and forth E-R, E-R.
びょ… びょい～んって
してますね 髪が｡
["If One Orange in the Box is Rotten, the Rest of Them Will Become Rotten Before You Realize It"]
(山崎)あれ？
Huh?
何やってんですか 旦那｡
What are you doing, master?
ひょっとして
旦那方もこの大会に？
Are you also participating in this tournament?
いや～ 奇遇ですね｡
Well, what a coincidence.
Ya-Yamazaki!
(新八/銀時)や 山崎！
♪♪～
(神楽)やっほ～い！
どけどけ どけどけ！
Woo-hoo!! Outta the way!
Scram!
邪魔ｱﾙ！ 女王様のお通りね！
The Queen's passing through!
Piece of cake!
楽勝ｱﾙ！ 賞金は私のものね！
The prize money's mine!
ｶﾞﾊﾊﾊﾊｯ！
(近藤)
快進撃は ここまでだ お嬢さん｡
This is where your merry stroll ends, young lady.
I won't let anyone run ahead of me!
何人たりとも
ｵﾚの前は走らせねえ！
お前は…｡
うお～っ！
You're...
てあ～っ！
(２人)うお～っ！
The chief asked me to participate.
(山崎)局長の誘いで
参加することになっちゃいまして｡
いや～ まいっちゃいましたよ｡
Put me in quite the fix.
副長を解放するためとか何とか➡
He was going on about freeing the Vice-Chief or something,
わけのわからないこと
言ってんですけど➡
こんな
恥ずかしいﾁｰﾑ衣装着せられて➡
but how am I supposed to understand what's going on when you put me
in this embarrassing uniform and tell me to run.
いきなり走れって
言われても意味わかんないでしょ｡
いや 別にお通ちゃんは
嫌いじゃないけど➡
Well, it's not that I don't like Otsu-chan or anything,
but I'm not a big enough fan to want to participate in an event like this.
こんな大会に
出場するほどじゃないし｡
ん！
(銀時)おい！
Hey.
そもそも 何でお通ちゃんの
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞになることが➡
Besides, I have no idea how becoming Otsu-chan's official fan club
is going to save the Vice-Chief, yeah?
副長を救うことになるのか
意味わかんないでしょ｡ それにね｡
On top of that..
《や やべえ！
やっぱｺｲﾂも ﾔﾂの仲間だ｡
Th-This is bad.
He's also one of them!
沖田に 山崎に ｺﾞﾘ…｡
それがﾔﾂのﾁｰﾑ》
Okita, Yamazaki, and the gorilla!
That's his team...
Th-This is bad, Gin-san!
《ま まずいです 銀さん！
If the committee finds out about Takachin, we're finished!
たかちんのこと
大会運営側にﾁｸられたら➡
ﾎﾞｸらもうおしまいです！
なんとか ごまかさなきゃ》
We have to cover this up!
ﾊﾊｯ 大変そうだな｡
じゃあ ｵﾚたち先急ぐんで｡
That sounds rough.
Well, we happen to be in a hurry so...
山崎さんもがんばってください！
Good luck, Yamazaki-san!
あ ちょっと旦那！
Ah, hold on, master!
ん ん～？
今から走ってももう遅いですって｡
It's too late to start running now.
We're dead last, you know.
ﾄﾞﾝｹﾂですよ ｵﾚで｡
あ ああうん｡
Y-Yeah...
You probably let someone else run up ahead so you could relax yourself, right?
どうせ旦那方も先に
誰かを走らせて 人任せにして➡
自分は 軽く流してたんでしょ｡
ん ん～｡
いいんですよ
見栄なんか張らなくても｡
You don't need to put on airs.
お おう｡
We have no choice!
《張らなきゃ ﾀﾞﾒなんだよ！
We don't have to worry about what place we're in since Kagura-chan's running up ahead,
神楽ちゃんを先に走らせてるから
順位は心配ないけど➡
たかちんの
負傷がﾊﾞﾚれば それも水の泡｡
but that'll all be for nothing if they find out about Takachin's injury!
何としても ｺﾞｰﾙまで誰にも➡
We must make it to the finish line without anybody noticing!
気取られないようにしなければ》
Uh, at the moment, a young girl and a large man are in the lead.
[ﾓﾆﾀ]ただいま
先頭を走るのは 少女と偉丈夫｡
[ﾓﾆﾀ]寺門通親衛隊と
通選組のﾒﾝﾊﾞｰであります｡
Members from the Tsu Terakado Fan Club and the Tsusengumi.
Neither is giving up an inch! This is amazing!
両者 一歩も譲りません｡
これは すごい!!
激しいﾃﾞｯﾄﾞﾋｰﾄを
繰り広げております｡
We've got an intense head-to-head race here!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]これは
どちらが勝つかは さておき➡
Regardless of which one pulls ahead,
both teams appear assured to make it out of the prelims...
まず 両ﾁｰﾑとも予選勝ち抜きは➡
堅そうで… あれ？
あっ ちょっと違う…｡
Er?
Wait, that's wrong!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]違うよ そっち！ これは
なんということでしょう!!
That's the wrong way!
What is this?!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]ﾄｯﾌﾟを走っていた２人➡
The two lead runners are so intent on their contest that they've gone the wrong way!
勝負に白熱するあまり
思いっきり道を間違っています！
[ﾓﾆﾀ]あ～っ 違う 違う!!
Ah, that's wrong!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]そっちじゃないって！
違うってば!!
That's the wrong way!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]ものすごい勢いで
ｺｰｽｱｳﾄしていく！
They're racing off course at a tremendous speed!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]みるみる ﾄｯﾌﾟから
離れていきます｡
Their rankings are starting to drop!
From heaven to hell!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]天国から地獄 これは まずい！
早くﾁｰﾑのﾒﾝﾊﾞｰが何とかしないと➡
This is bad!
The other members of their teams have to do something,
両ﾁｰﾑとも 予選敗退は
まぬがれません!!
or neither team will make it out of the prelims!
何をしてんだ！ ｱｲﾂは!!
What the hell is she doing?!
他のﾒﾝﾊﾞｰが
何とかしなきゃいけないって➡
What do you mean, the other members have to do something?!
今から行って
何とかなるんですか？
Isn't it a bit late to do anything?!
Are we supposed to catch up while carrying Takachin!
たかちん背負って
追いつけるんですか!?
This is the pits!
最悪だ！ あのﾊﾞｶに
先陣任せたのが間違いだった!!
It was stupid of me to send her up ahead!
旦那 旦那｡ 後ろ 後ろ｡
Master, master.
Behind you. Behind you.
なんか いろいろ
引っかかってますけど｡
You've picked up all kinds of junk.
(銀時/新八)うお～っ!!
あの…
大丈夫なんですか？ その人｡
Uh, is that guy okay?
さっきから
全然 動いてないんですけど｡
He hasn't moved at all.
えっ!?
Huh?!
Did something happen?
(山崎)何か あったんですか？
ぜ… 全然だけど！
N-Nothing at all!
全然 大丈夫だけど！
He's absolutely fine!
He's just tired after running too fast at the beginning!
ちょっと序盤で飛ばしすぎて
疲れてるだけだし うん！
いや… でも…｡
Yeah, but...
(唸り声)
He's got a stray dog biting down really hard on him.
思いっきり 野良犬に
噛みつかれてますけど｡
ものすごい食いつきですけど｡
Those are the eyes of a dog hungering for dead flesh.
死肉をあさりにきた目
なんですけど 大丈夫なんですか？
Is that okay?
Absolutely okay!
全然だけど！
ｺｲﾂ 実家で犬飼ってるから➡
He's got a few dogs at his old home!
なつかれやすいんじゃ
ないかな？ うん！
Maybe dogs just love him?!
いや でも…｡
Yeah, but...
(山崎)なんか 後ろに
鎌 持った 変なおっさんも➡
There's a weird old guy with a scythe bearing down on you.
ぶら下がってるんですけど
大丈夫なんですか？
Is that okay?
全然だけど！ あれ
実家のお父さんじゃないかな｡
Absolutely okay!
Maybe it's his dad from back home?!
応援しにきたんだよ きっと！
He must have come to cheer him on!
(山崎)いや でも…
背中に 翼生えたおばさんも➡
Yeah, but...
There's also an old lady with wings on her back bearing down on you.
ぶら下がってますけど
大丈夫なんですか？
Is that okay?
It's his mom!
お母さんだね！
夫婦揃って来てくれたんだよ｡
Both of them came!
What a wonderful family!
いや～ いい家族だね！
旦那！ なんか もう
全部 剥き出しなんですけど!!
Master! He's completely exposed now!
ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫なんですか!?
ちょっと!!
Are you sure he's okay?! Hey!
全然だけど!! 剥き出しだけど➡
Absolutely okay!
He may be completely exposed, but we've got a hat covering it so we're okay!
[Note: Gin is hinting that Takachin has phimosis, a physical condition that affects men. Look it up.]
ある一点においては
ちゃんと帽子 かぶってるから！
小粋なｻﾝﾊﾞｲｻﾞｰ かぶってるから!!
A little sun visor's covering it!
銀さん！ ﾑﾘです!!
もう ｶﾊﾞｰ ﾑﾘです！
Gin-san!
This is impossible!
This is impossible to cover up!
このままじゃ
たかちんの身がもちません！
Takachin's body won't be able to bear all of this!
何より 予選勝ち抜く前に
公然猥褻でﾊﾟｸられます!!
And worst of all, he'll be charged with public indecency before we make it out of the prelims!
ｸｿｯ… しかたねえ
背に腹は替えられん｡
Damn it...
I have no choice!
Sacrifices must be made at times!
新八 追い上げは任せた！
Shinpachi!
I'm counting on you to catch-up!
銀さん！ どこに…｡
Gin-san!
Where are you going?!
ｵﾚは たかちんを
いったん病院へ連れていく｡
I'll take Taka-chin to the hospital for now!
銀さん ﾑﾘです！
Gin-san, it's no use!
If you take him to a doctor in that condition, he'll be hospitalized in no time!
その状態で医者に診せれば
即入院ですよ!!
棄権は免れません！
We won't be able to avoid his disqualification!
治療が終わったら
必ず連れて戻ってくる｡ 約束だ｡
I vow to bring him back once he's been looked at!
I promise!
だから それまで頼んだぞ 新八！
So I'm counting on you in the meantime, Shinpachi!
Gin-san!
銀さん！ そこ
泌尿器形成外科なんですけど…｡
That's a clinic for urologic plastic surgery!
What are you having him looked at for?!
いったい 何の治療
するつもりなんですか!?
終わったね 新八君｡
It's over, Shinpachi-kun.
あんな状態で
戦線に復帰できるわけがない｡
He won't be able to make it back in that state.
まあ ｷﾐらの分も
ｵﾚたちが がんばるから➡
Well, we'll work hard enough for your share.
おとなしくｷﾞﾌﾞｱｯﾌﾟして
観衆に回ってなよ｡
Just give up quietly and join the spectators.
ﾎﾞｸは あきらめませんよ！
I won't give up!
銀さんが約束したからには
必ず あの２人は戻ってくる！
Gin-san promised, so they'll definitely return!
ﾎﾞｸに できることは 彼らを信じて
ただ前に進むことだけです!!
All I can do is believe in them and move on!
あ～あ あんなに
熱くなっちゃって ﾑﾀﾞなことを｡
Aw, he's all fired up now.
What a waste of effort.
通選組の勝ちは
もう決まってる…｡
The Tsusengumi's victory is all but...
なかなか速えじゃねえか｡
He's pretty quick.
あれだったら
何とかなんじゃねえの？
早っ！
We might have a chance at this rate.
That was fast!
なんだ？ 早かったら悪いのか？
What? You got a problem with me coming back so fast?
いや… あまりにも
早すぎるでしょ!?
No, wasn't that a little too fast?
あのｹｶﾞ人は？ まさか
そのへんに捨ててきたんですか？
Where's that injured guy?
Did you just dump him off somewhere?
いや 治療が終わったら
すぐ こっちに駆けつけるって｡
No, he said he'd race over as soon as he was done being treated.
またまた… 時間稼ぎして
何の意味があるんです？
You're such a kidder.
What's the point in buying a little time?
どうせ
戻ってきやしないんでしょ？
He won't be coming back.
あっ 来た｡
えっ？
Ah, there he is.
Huh?
お～い こっち こっち｡
Hey!
Over here!
いや～ よかったな｡
大事にならなくてよ｡
Man, it's a good thing it wasn't anything serious.
Besides, you're too weak.
そもそも お前は ひ弱すぎんだよ｡
もっと体とか鍛えないとﾀﾞﾒだぜ｡
You need to work out more.
なあ？ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ｡
Yeah, Taka-tin?
(山崎)誰!?
Who is that?!
これ 誰だ？
まったくの別人じゃないすか！
Who is this person?!
Isn't this a completely different person?!
誰なんですか？
この ふてぶてしい外国人!!
Who is this brazen foreigner?!
は？ ﾜｯﾄ ﾄﾞｩ ﾕｰ ｾｲ？
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝだろ｡
Huh? What do you say?
It's Taka-tin.
どこから どう見ても
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ以外の何者でもねえだろ｡
It's obviously Taka-tin and nobody else.
ｻﾞｯﾂ ﾄｩﾙｰ｡
That's true.
No, it's obviously a completely different person!
いや どこからどう見ても
別人以外の何者でもないよ｡
360度 あらゆる角度から見ても
１か所たりとも かぶってないよ！
Look at this guy from any angle and any position and this guy's got nothing on him!
そうだよ かぶってねえよ｡
Yep, nothing on him.
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝは 治療を終えて
退院してきたからな｡
Since Taka-tin was just released from surgery.
何の治療だよ!? ｷｬﾗ設定だよ！
発注ﾐｽってﾚﾍﾞﾙじゃねえぞ｡
What kind of surgery?!
I'm talking about his character!
It's not like you ordered the wrong guy here!
つうか ﾀｶﾃｨﾝって何だ？ なんで
ﾁﾝだけ英語発音になってんだ!!
And what do you mean, Taka-tin?!
Why are you speaking in English?!
ｳｫｲｳｫ～ｲ
ｲﾁｬﾓﾝつけるのは よせよ｡
Hey, now.
Don't try to pick a fight here.
かぶるも何も 本人だからね｡
丸かぶりだからね｡ ﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
He's the real deal. 100% genuine.
Authentic stuff, yeah.
中途半端な英語発音 やめろよ｡
ｲﾗｯとすんだよ！
Lose the crappy English accent! It's pissing me off!
Now, now. Think back.
まあ まあ 思い出してみろよ｡
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝといえば
あのﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝのような ﾘｰｾﾞﾝﾄ｡
Taka-tin had that French bread-looking pompadour.
He's just carrying a loaf of French bread in his hand!
(山崎)ただ ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ
手に持ってるだけだろうが！
You could at least put the bread on his head!
せめて 頭に
ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝのせてこいよ！
Why is he just standing there?!
なんで 棒立ちなんだよ！
なんで ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ立ちなんだよ！
Why is he standing there with French bread?!
Well, the treatment being what it was...
まあ 治療が治療だけにな｡
A man becomes an adult when he's had the hat down there removed.
男は あそこの帽子が脱げたら
大人の仲間入りだからな｡
He's dropped the sun visor to stand out where everyone can see.
ｻﾝﾊﾞｲｻﾞｰを脱ぎ捨て
日の当たるところに出てきた｡
そのへんの気構えが 彼を➡
[Note: Gintoki is taking about a circumcision and the surgical operation used to fix phimosis.]
So he's probably trying to act a little more mature.
ちょっぴり大人びたふうに
見せているんだろう｡
Like I said! What kind of treatment was it?!
(山崎)だから 何の治療を
してきたんだ！
How could he possibly have turned into a huge adult who can't fit into a T-shirt?!
どこをどうやったら
ﾊｯﾋﾟをＴｼｬﾂみたいに➡
着こなせる大人になれるんだよ！
まあ 生まれてから➡
Well, he finally dropped the turtleneck he's had since he was born.
[Note: Turtleneck sweaters are often used in ads as a symbol of phimosis.]
今まで着ていたﾀｰﾄﾙﾈｯｸを
やっと脱ぎ捨てたからね｡
(ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ)ﾀｲﾑ ｲｽﾞ ﾏﾈｰ｡
Time is money.
Oh, we don't have time for this.
おう そうだな
こんなことしてる場合じゃないな｡
We need to be on our way.
早く行かなきゃな｡
(山崎)今 完全に➡
He just spoke in English.
英語しゃべったよね？ もう全然
ﾓﾉﾏﾈとかするつもりないよね｡
He's not even trying to pretend to be him!
ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ食べてるし！
And he's eating the French bread!
One hour, ten thousand yen.
１時間 １万円｡
２時間 ２万円｡
Two hours, twenty thousand yen.
その間 私 ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ｡ ｵｰｹｰ？
During that time, I'm Taka-tin.
Okay?
Okay. Okay.
ｵｰｹｰ ｵｰｹｰ｡
３時間 ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ３本｡
Three hours, three loaves of French bread.
４時間 ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ４本｡
ｱｰﾊｰ ｵｰｹｰ？
Four hours, four loaves of French bread.
Okay?
Why does his compensation become French bread after three hours?!
なんで ３時間以降
報酬 ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝに変わってんだよ！
It obviously isn't okay!
ｵｰｹｰのわけねえだろ！
結局 ２万しかもらえねえだろが！
He's only getting twenty thousand out of this!
ｵｰｹｰ ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ！
ｵｰｹｰなのかよ！
Okay! French bread!
You're okay with it?!
金より ﾊﾟﾝかよ！
これは明らかに不正ですよ！
Bread over money?!
This is obviously fraud.
替え玉以外の何者でもないですよ｡
He's nothing more than a substitute.
悪いけど 大会側に
報告させてもらいますから！
Sorry, but I have to report this to the committee.
みんな真面目にやってるのに
見過ごせませんよ｡
Everybody's serious about this!
I can't let this slide!
いた～！
Ow!
ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ 固い！ ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ 痛い！
The French bread is hard!
The French bread hurts!
Everybody's serious about this?
みんな真面目？ おい
ふざけたこと言ってんじゃねえぞ｡
Hey, don't give me that bullshit. Hey, now.
おう ｺﾗ！
は？
Want me to tell you how Takachin got injured in the first place? Huh?
お前 たかちんが➡
なんで あんな重傷負ったか
教えてやろうか あん？
The prelims are yielding a whirlwind of events.
[ﾏｲｸ]予選から 波乱の展開に
なってきました！
[ﾏｲｸ]参加者のうち その半数が
ﾄｯﾌﾟ２人の爆走に巻き込まれ棄権｡
Half of the participants are out after being caught up in the rampage of the front two.
そして そのﾄｯﾌﾟ２人が
道を間違え行方不明｡
And the front two are missing after going the wrong way.
At the moment, the last stragglers from the remaining half
え～ 現在 残った半数の最後尾➡
ﾋﾞﾘｹﾂ集団が 彼らの消えた
５km地点を通過していきます｡
have passed the five kilometer mark where they disappeared.
寺門通親衛隊 通選組
勝利を目前に➡
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club and the Tsusengumi
have clawed their way from the depths of hell in search of victory!
とうとう ﾋﾞﾘｹﾂにまで
落ちてしまいました｡
Quite frankly, they have no chance of bouncing back.
これは正直 もう巻き返しは
不可能でしょう 非常に残念です｡
Very unfortunate.
ﾄｯﾌﾟﾚﾍﾞﾙの実力を持つ ２ﾁｰﾑが
なんと 予選敗… うん？
Two of the top teams falling in the prelims...
[ﾏｲｸ]あ あれは…｡
Ah...
That's...
The person racing over the countless fallen bodies of otakus at a tremendous speed...
[ﾏｲｸ]無数に転がる
ｵﾀｸたちの屍の上を➡
とてつもない速さで
こちらに迫ってくるのが➡
C-Could it be?!
ま まさか…
あれは あれは～！
That's... That's...
Here it is!
[ﾏｲｸ]きた～ 寺門通親衛隊！
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club has clawed their way from the depths of hell in search of victory!
[ﾏｲｸ]勝利を再び
この手につかまんと➡
地獄の底より
這い上がってきた～！
[ﾏｲｸ]しかし ﾋﾞﾘの彼と ﾄｯﾌﾟの間は➡
However, a large gap has opened between the leaders and the stragglers.
すでに
大きく開いてしまっています｡
It will be very difficult to overcome their lead!
この差を巻き返すのは
至難の業です！
ﾊｱ ﾊｱ ﾊｱ！
《こんなところで負けられない
負けるわけには いかないんだ》
I can't lose here!
I can't let myself lose!
うお～!!
Whoa! He's speeding up!
[ﾏｲｸ]おっと それでも負けじと
ﾍﾟｰｽを上げた！
[ﾏｲｸ]先行集団を一気に追い上げ
追い抜きにかかります！
He's already caught up to the frontrunners and is attempting to pass them!
うお～！
(土方)ﾌｫｰﾒｰｼｮﾝ 玄武｡
Formation Genbu.
Oh?
[ﾏｲｸ]あら～？ これは
これは どういうことだ？
What... What is this?
[ﾏｲｸ]先行集団が 突然 陣形を組み➡
The frontrunners have abruptly created a formation to block the Tsu Terakado Fan Club's path!
寺門通親衛隊の行く手を
阻んだ！
[ﾏｲｸ]壁 まるで壁です
巨大なｵﾀｸの肉壁が➡
A wall! It's like a wall!
A large wall of otaku prevents him from advancing!
親衛隊を 一歩も前へ通しません｡
[ﾏｲｸ]いったい
どういうことでしょうか？
What is going on here?
How could all these scattered teams move with such coordination?!
[ﾏｲｸ]他ﾁｰﾑが混在する集団が➡
これだけ
統率された動きをみせるとは！
《まさか…》
It couldn't be...
(土方)まったく めでてえﾔﾂらだ｡
What a naive bunch of people...
Between the committee running this contest and your little fan club...
大会を運営している連中も
ﾃﾒｴら 親衛隊も｡
この大会は 5,000人の出場者
つまり およそ1,000ﾁｰﾑが➡
Five thousand participants in this tournament.
In other words, over a thousand teams fighting for the title of Official Fan Club...
公式ﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞの座をめぐって
互いに争う か｡
そんな甘っちょろい大会
なんぞじゃねえことに➡
You still haven't noticed that this contest isn't all fun and games?
まだ気づかねえのか？
1,000ﾁｰﾑ対 １ﾁｰﾑ
5,000人対 ４人｡
A thousand teams versus one.
Five thousand versus four.
(土方)ここにいるのは ﾊﾅから
ﾃﾒｴらと ｵﾚたちだけだ｡
The only people in this competition are yours and mine.
この大会に出場し
今 ここに立つｵﾀｸどもは➡
All of the otaku standing here after entering the tournament are my pawns, excluding your group.
ﾃﾒｴら以外
すべて ｵﾚの手ごまなんだよ｡
な… ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな！
Th-That's impossible...
ｺｲﾂら全員 通選組の傘下だと？
All of them belong to the Tsusengumi?!
They're all our enemies?!
ｺｲﾂら全員 ﾎﾞｸらの敵？
そんな まさか…｡
No way...
It can't be!
ここまで巨大な勢力に
なっていたなんて！
How could you have become such a large force...?
The battle was over before it even began.
勝負は 始まる前から
ついていたんだ｡
そう この大会は ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ
決定戦なんかじゃねえ｡
Yes.
This isn't a contest for becoming the Official Fan Club.
ﾌｰｯ ただの儀式｡
It's merely a ritual.
A little celebration to cleanse Toshi.
ﾄｯｼｰを浄化させるための
ただの祭ごとに過ぎねえんだよ｡
そしてﾃﾒｴらは
そこに捧げられる生け贄｡
And you people are the sacrifices.
Nobody likes sacrifices that don't know when to give up.
あきらめの悪い贄は嫌われるぜ｡
お前に必要なのは
戦う覚悟じゃない｡
You shouldn't be roaring for a fight. You should be accepting your fate.
運命を受け入れる覚悟だ｡
[ﾏｲｸ]これはなんと
先行集団の中に➡
What's this?!
A member of the Tsusengumi was among the frontrunners!
まだ通選組のﾒﾝﾊﾞｰが
まぎれていた！
We were unable to hear the conversation,
話は よく聞こえませんでしたが➡
but it's believed that he's leading multiple teams in working together to block the Tsu Terakado Fan Club!
どうやら
強豪 寺門通親衛隊を下すため➡
彼を中心に複数のﾁｰﾑが
手を組んだように思われます！
まるで 十戒のごとく
ｵﾀｸの波が割れていく！
The waves of otaku are parting like the Ten Commandments!
The Tsusengumi has instantly jumped to the top!
通選組 またたく間に
順位を上げていきます！
一方 寺門通親衛隊は…｡
On the other hand, the Tsu Terakado Fan Club...
うおぉ～!!
Oh! The Tsu Terakado Fan Club has charged into the wall!
[ﾏｲｸ]おっと 寺門通親衛隊
ｵﾀｸの壁へ突撃した！
しかし ｵﾀｸの肉壁に阻まれ
まったく身動きが取れません！
However, the wall of otaku is preventing him from making a move!
《ｸｿｯ… ｸｿｯ！ あきらめない！
絶対 あきらめないぞ!!
Damn it! Damn it!
I won't give up!
I refuse to give up!
約束したんだ 銀さんと！
I made a promise with Gin-san!
I'm sure that Gin-san will keep this team alive!
銀さんは きっとﾁｰﾑの命を
つなげてくれる!!
I must keep our hopes alive!
ﾎﾞｸは… 勝利への道を
つなげなければ!!
見つけるんだ 道を！
I must find a path...
どんなに細くてもいい｡
I don't care how thin it may be.
I will find the ray of light that leads to victory!
勝利につながる ひと筋の光を➡
見つけるんだ！》
[ﾏｲｸ]ｺｰｽは ７ｷﾛ地点の
橋に さしかかりました｡
We now move to the bridge at the seven kilometer mark of the course.
ｺﾞｰﾙまで残り３ｷﾛ｡
Only three kilometers to the finish line.
寺門通親衛隊は
ﾋﾞﾘｹﾂに押しやられたままです｡
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club remains stuck in dead last!
あっ！
It will be difficult to change the situation!
[ﾏｲｸ]この状況は
どうにも くつがえしがたい｡
Is this the end for their fan club?!
どうなる親衛隊!?
もはや ここまでか！
《見つけた！》
Found it...
ぬおぉ～!!
うぉらぁ～!!
[ﾏｲｸ]橋の欄干！ 寺門通親衛隊
道であって道でない➡
The rail of the bridge!
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club
has found a path to victory where none existed, on the thin rail of the bridge!
細い欄干の上に
勝利の道を見出した！
予想外の動きに
他ﾁｰﾑ対応しきれない！
The other teams are unable to cope with this unexpected development!
義経よろしく
華麗に橋の上を跳ねていく！
Like Yoshitsune, He's gracefully tearing across the bridge!
[Note: Reference to Yoshitsune Minamoto from Heian era. Legend says he dueled legendary warrior monk Benkei on Gojo Bridge.]
The otaku are gathering onto the bridge to block the fan club's path!
親衛隊を止めようと橋の上に
ｵﾀｸが密集しております！
Will he make it past this wall of bodies?!
抜けられるのか この肉の壁を！
Can he surpass his own limits?!
抜けられるのか 己の限界の壁を！
あっ！
A little more... Just a little more!
《あとちょっと！
あと もうちょっとだ！
これが 最後のﾁｬﾝｽだ！
This is our last chance!
I'm definitely going to take it!
絶対に つかみとるぞ！
Victory! Victory for all of us!
勝利を… みんなで勝利を！》
(ｵﾀｸたち)うおぉ～！
よくやった ぱっつぁん！
もう十分だ｡
Well done, Patsuan.
That's enough.
We'll handle the rest.
あとは ｵﾚたちに任せな！
あっ！
Gin-san!
銀さん！ たかち…｡
じゃあ 頼むわ｡
Takachi...
So we're counting on you,
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ！
ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ！
Taka-tin.
French bread!
Huh?
えっ… 誰それ？
Who is that?
[ﾏｲｸ]寺門通親衛隊
味方をｴｻに敵ﾁｰﾑ殲滅!!
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club has used one of their own as bait to destroy the other teams!
ﾊｲ！
ﾍｲ！
[To Be Continued]
A Little Ginpachi Sensei!
Okay, we have some extra time, so I'll read a few letters.
Uh, a question from pen name Odd Jobs Rule, Shinsengumi...
is okay?
Nice to meet you.
I just noticed something.
Shinpachi is a fan of Otsu.
And Kagura likes enka.
[Note: Enka is Japanese traditional popular music.]
So what kind of music does Gin-san like?
I can't think of anything off the top of my head, so please let me know.
Okay, I'll give you your answer.
Gin-san doesn't listen to music.
He hums a few commercial jingles every now and then.
[Note: Episode #133]
So you remember back when I sang A Thousand Winds?
After that episode aired, the voice actor's mother called to say,
[Note: The voice actor is Tomokazu Sugita.]
"Tomokazu, do a better job of singing."
Sorry, that's how this character is supposed to be.
And on a different note,
Okita probably listens to comic storytellings.
[Note: Japanese comic storytelling (Rakugo) is Japanese verbal entertainment.]
You can imagine him listening to the stuff, right?
はい 時間あまっちゃったんで
お便り読みます｡
Uh, here's another one.
A question from pen name Kaishu Katsu should be in GinTama.
ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ 万事屋 大ﾌｧﾝ!!
新選組は… 普通？
さんからの質問｡
Hello.
Excuse me, I have a question to ask.
While watching the ending credits,
｢はじめまして｡ 実は さっき
気づいたことがあるんですけど➡
it says that Yuu Saito assisted in the production.
新八って
お通が好きじゃないですか｡
で 神楽は演歌｡
He's the current editor for the manga, right?
じゃあ 銀さんが好きな曲は
何ですか？
When Onishi was the editor, it said that Kohei Onishi assisted in the production.
あまり ﾋﾟﾝとこないんで
お願いします｣｡
はい ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘお答えしましょう｡
How exactly do they assist in the production of the GinTama anime?
銀さんは 基本 音楽を聴きません｡
Please let me know.
ＣＭの曲を口ずさむ程度です｡
Okay, I'll give you your answer.
だから 以前
｢千の風｣歌ったときも➡
They don't do anything at all.
うろ覚えだったんですね｡
Every week, they hold so-called meetings with the anime staff where they drink using their company money.
ｵﾝｴｱのあと中の人に
お母さんから➡
ともかず もっとちゃんと
歌いなさい って➡
So Nakasaki, the new editor.
電話がきましたが
すみません そういう設定です｡
Enjoy the company's money next week.
あと関係ないけど
沖田は 落語とか聞いてます｡
なんか聞いてそうでしょ ｱｲﾂ｡
えっと もう一枚｡
ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ 勝海舟 『銀魂』に出して
さんからの質問｡
｢こんにちは｡ さっそくですが
質問があります｡
ｴﾝﾄﾞﾛｰﾙを見ていたら➡
協力 斉藤優と
書いてあったのですが➡
この人って
現在の漫画の担当さんですよね｡
以前 大西さんが
担当のときは➡
協力
大西恒平でした｡
彼らは 『銀魂』のｱﾆﾒを作るとき➡
どのように
協力しているのでしょうか｡
教えてください｣｡
はい ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘお答えします｡
何も協力していません｡
毎週 打ち合わせと称して➡
会社の金で
ｱﾆﾒｽﾀｯﾌと飲んでるだけです｡
じゃあ 新担当の中崎！
来週も会社の金で よろしく！
Who are you?!
Who the hell are you?!
The next episode...
"From a foreigner's perspective, you're the foreigner."
"From an alien's perspective, you're the alien."
Yeah!
So who the hell are you?!
Taka-tin.
[Finally, the main round for the battle to become the Tsu Terakado Official Fan Club begins!!]
[The Fan Club versus the Tsusengumi. They begin with a quiz!]
[See you next time.]